Away with Words is a comedy, drama film directed by Christopher Doyle.
A Japanese man and a gay bar-owner in Hong Kong drink beer as
they talk about their childhood and experiences.
Asano Takashi, played by Tadanobu Asano.
Georgina, played by Georgina Hobson.
Christa, played by Christa Hughes.
Kevin, played by Kevin Sherlock.
Susie, played by Mavis Xu.
Asano Takashi (Boy), played by Takanori Kubo.
Away with Words (known also by its Chinese title 三條人, roughly translated as Three Life-stories, and its Japanese title 孔雀, translated as Peacock) is a 1999 auteur
trilingual (Japanese, English, Cantonese) film by Christopher Doyle co-scripted by Doyle and Tony Rayns and starring Tadanobu Asano, Kevin Sherlock and Mavis Xu.
The film, shot in a jazzy, free-wheeling style and featuring Doyle's signature hyper-kinetic, oversaturated photography and eccentric humor, focuses on a trip that Asano's character takes to
Hong Kong and his encounters with off-beat personalities populating the metropolitan landscape (among them, a beer-drinking amnesiac gay bar owner portrayed by Kevin Sherlock).
Another narrative thread relies on flashbacks into
Asano's character's childhood in Okinawa.
The protagonist suffers from overbearing excesses of his
memory, mnemonic associations and synesthesia.
The emerging human attachments provide an emotional center and a source of serenity to offset the
rampage of the protagonist's mind and tame the lavish disarray of urban imagery.
The film credits Jorge Luis Borges (presumably Funes the
Memorious) and Alexander Luria for inspiration.
Many aspects of Asano's character (memory excess, profound synesthesia, arranging memories visually along roads, wordplay, struggling with an onslaught of associations, comments about
restaurant music and its effect on food taste, the waking-for-school scene) are directly borrowed from Luria's real life case study of Solomon Shereshevskii, The Mind of a Mnemonist.
The film was screened in the Un Certain Regard
section at the 1999 Cannes Film Festival.
The film explores themes of gay club, foreign language, language, gay theme.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.